<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "MSS_Arquillian_Framework_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="Introduction_to_the_MSS_Arquillian_Framework">
	<title>Introduction to the Mobicents Arquillian Sip Servlets Extension
	</title>
	<!-- Introduction to Arquillian -->
	<para>
		Arquillian is a container-oriented test framework. It picks up where
		unit tests leave off, targeting the integration of application code
		inside a real runtime environment. Just as Java EE 5 simplified the
		server programming model by providing declarative services for POJOs,
		Arquillian equips tests with container lifecycle management and
		enrichment. You can learn more on Arquillian here
		<ulink url="http://arquillian.org/">Arquillian Home</ulink>
	</para>

	<para>With the Mobicents Sip Servlets Arquillian framework Mobicents
		team brings the power and benefits of the Arquillian framework to the
		Sip Servlets world.
	</para>
	<para>Integration testing for Sip Servlets now becomes as much simple
		or as much complicated as you wish. No need to extend and use complex
		classes and structures anymore in order to test your Sip Servlets
		application. But on the other hand, you can go ahead and do it if you
		need.
	</para>
	<para>With the Mobicents Arquillian testing framework, you have the
		choice to work with a standard environment that will fit most of the
		cases, or go ahead and parameterize the testing environment as much as
		you wish in order to meet your needs.
	</para>

	<formalpara id="MSS_Arquillian_Framework_Container_Support">
		<title>Container Support</title>
		<para>Mobicents
			Arquillian testing framework now supports &PLATFORM_NAME;
			Sip Servlets 1.7 - Tomcat 6.x
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara id="MSS_Arquillian_Framework_Parts">
		<title>MSS Arquillian Framework Parts</title>
		<para>The Mobicents Arquillian testing framework consists of the
			following parts
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>The embedded Mobicents Sip Servlets container that the
					application will run.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A sip client to interact with your application. For this we
					are using SipUnit but you are free to use any sip client fits
					your needs. We are collaborating with CafeSip developers on the SipUnit
					project in
					order to provide new features, fix bugs etc.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</formalpara>
</chapter>
